Guide to the Afrika Bambaataa hip hop archive, circa 1972-2016.
Bambaataa, Afrika hip hop archive,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Afrika Bambaataa hip hop archive, circa 1972-2016.
8094
Afrika Bambaataa, 1957-
600 cubic feet.
Vinyl records and other A/V Recordings, Financial Records, Manuscripts, Memorabilia, Photocopies, Photographs, Printed Materials, Publications.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Approximately 40,000 sound recordings representing Bambaataa's music collection from the 1970s to the present. The archive also includes books, documents, and files relating to the founding and spread of the Universal Zulu Nation; and videos, papers, and clothing.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Afrika Bambaataa is an American disc jockey, singer, and songwriter from the South Bronx, New York. Often called the “Godfather” of Hip Hop, Bambaataa has helped to define Hip Hop since it emerged in the South Bronx in the 1970s. One of a handful of Hip Hop's 1970s originators, Bambaataa gave Hip Hop its name, and was the first to define its core artistic elements - DJing, rapping, break dancing, and graffiti art - under one cultural umbrella. His cultural organization, the Universal Zulu Nation, has helped to spread Hip Hop culture throughout the world. His genre-defining 1982 song "Planet Rock" and subsequent electro-funk tracks have become icons of hip-hop and electronic music. In 2007 he was nominated for induction into the Rock and Roll Hall of Fame.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Approximately 40,000 sound recordings representing Bambaataa's music collection from the 1970s to the present. The archive also includes books, documents, and files relating to the founding and spread of the Universal Zulu Nation; and videos, papers, and clothing.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Afrika Bambaataa, 1957-; Universal Zulu Nation (Organization)
Subjects:
African American youth -- Social life and customs.; Disc jockeys.; Electronic music.; Funk (Music).; Hip-hop.; Hip-hop -- Influence.; Hip-hop -- History. -- United States; Music -- Social aspects.; Race relations.; Rap (Music); Rap (Music) -- Political aspects.; Rap musicians.; Hip-hop -- New York.; Rap (Music) -- New York.; Hip-hop; Rap (Music); Rap musicians; Social history
Places:
Bronx (New York, N.Y.) -- Social conditions -- 20th century.; New York (State) -- New York; New York (State) -- Bronx; United States
Form and Genre Terms:
History
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Access to collection restricted until completion of processing, with the exception of vinyl records that have been individually cataloged.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Manuscripts
a. School Papers and Assignments
b. Africa Trip
c. Soul Scrapbooks and Music Writing
d. Notebooks and Miscellaneous Manuscripts
e. Lyrics and Poems
f. Bronx River Neighborhood Center
g. Phone and Contact Lists
Series II. Flyers
Series III. Photographs
Series IV. Personal Papers
a. Personal Papers
b. Press About Bambaataa
c. Catalogs and Mail
Series V. Universal Zulu Nation Documents
a. Infinity Lessons
b. Administration
Series VI. Stage Costumes and Clothing
Series VII. Periodicals and Publications
a. Small Press Publications
b. Periodicals
c. Publications from 3410 De Reimer Ave. Bronx, NY
d. Other Publications
Series VIII. Moving images and audio recordings
a. Video cassettes
a. Audio cassettes
Series IX. Music collection
12 inch vinyl
Sureshots and altered/obscured
Numbered by Bambaataa
Annotated, not numbered (Alphabetical by artist)
A-D
E-H
I-L
L-O
P-S
T-Z
Numbers, unknown and various
Second alpha sequence
Cataloged individually
Not annotated (Alphabetical by artist)
A
B
C
D
E
F
G
H
I
J
K
L
M
N
O
P
Q
R
S
Afrika Bambaataa recordings
Renegades of Rhythm Tour
Test pressings and white labels (not yet cataloged)
Compilations (not yet cataloged)
7 inch vinyl
Numbered (not yet cataloged)
Annotated not numbered (not yet cataloged)
No annotations (not yet cataloged)
Acetates and
Cassettes (not yet cataloged)
CDs (not yet cataloged)
Series X. Ephemera
CONTAINER LIST
- Manuscripts, 1969-1984
  Arranged chronologically by title within subject groupings.
  - School Papers and Assignments, 1969-1977
    - Dolly Madison, 1969 (Box 526, Folder 1)
    - The Unbelievable Adventure of Francisco Pizarro, 1969 (Box 526, Folder 2)
    - The Paleoyic Era, 1969-11-10 (Box 526, Folder 3)
    - The Jungle Book, 1970-02-20 (Box 526, Folder 5)
    - I Have a Dream About the Future, 1970-09-28 (Box 526, Folder 6)
    - Mohammed, 1971 (Box 526, Folder 7)
    - Dark Shadows, 1971 (Box 526, Folder 8)
    - What Needs to be Change in the Parish, 1971 (Box 526, Folder 9)
    - Sly and the Family Stone, Undated (Box 526, Folder 10)
    - I Was a Black Panther by Chuck Moor, 1971 (Box 526, Folder 11)
    - St. Anthony's Class of '71 Yearbook, 1971 (Box 526, Folder 12)
    - English 165 exam, 1971-10-22 (Box 526, Folder 13)
    - Christopher Columbus, 1972 (Box 531, Folder 9)
    - Cloud-Higher, 1972 (Box 526, Folder 14)
    - Giuseppe Garibaldi, 1972 (Box 531, Folder 12)
    - Guess Who, 1972 (Box 526, Folder 15)
    - The Life and Hell That One Black Boy Had in Catholic School for Two Years, 1972 (Box 526, Folder 16)
    - Mustapha Kemal Ataturk, 1972 (Box 531, Folder 11)
    - Prince Clemens Von Metternich, 1972 (Box 531, Folder 10)
    - Robespierre, 1972 (Box 531, Folder 13)
    - Music, 1972-02-09 (Box 526, Folder 17)
    - Engl 337A-Burn the Witch, 1972-09-21 (Box 526, Folder 18)
    - Engl 337A, 1972-09-30 (Box 526, Folder 19)
    - Sly and the Family Stone Concert, 1973-12 (Box 526, Folder 20)
    - Poem-I Wish, 1973 (Box 526, Folder 22)
    - Alphabet with Meaning, 1973 (Box 526, Folder 23)
    - Brutality to Policemen, 1973 (Box 526, Folder 24)
    - Criminology Textbooks, 1970-1974 (Box 526, Folder 4)
    - Criminology-Outline of Term Paper, 1973-10-09 (Box 526, Folder 25)
    - Criminology-Can Murder Ever Be Acceptable, 1973-12-06 (Box 526, Folder 26)
    - Creative Writing-Thinking to Myself, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 27)
    - Creative Writing-Character Sketch-The Mystery Person and Persons, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 28)
    - Creative Writing-Free Association-Music, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 29)
    - Creative Writing-It's Snowing, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 30)
    - John Nolt Chaplin Middle Passage, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 31)
    - Creative Writing-Character Sketch, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 32)
    - Blackness is These Special People, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 33)
    - Health, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 34)
    - Definitions (Death, Happiness, Freedom, Summer, Hate), 1974 (Box 526, Folder 35)
    - Hygiene, 1974 (Box 526, Folder 36)
    - Read and To Have Knowledge, 1974-03-21 (Box 526, Folder 37)
    - Creative Writing-Picture Scene, 1974-03-22 (Box 526, Folder 38)
    - Poems with a Thought, 1974-05-16 (Box 526, Folder 39)
    - World History assignments, 1974-07 (Box 545, Folder 4)
    - American Government assignments and readings, 1974-09-1974-10 (Box 545, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous High School, 1974 (Box 531, Folder 14)
    - Eng 528 Scrap, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 40)
    - Eng 528-Gang Revolution, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 41)
    - Ancient Egypt Africa, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 42)
    - Power, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 43)
    - How People Feel about Police, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 44)
    - An Idea or Thought (Poem), 1975 (Box 526, Folder 45)
    - Black American History, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 46)
    - Stand/Fight the Police, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 47)
    - What I Think Will Happen if New York City Defaults, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 48)
    - Diets and Diet Food Products, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 49)
    - Black Society, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 50)
    - Central America Trip Essay, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 51)
    - From the Planet Sunstar to the Planet Earth, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 52)
    - Taking from the Book the Rights of Students, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 53)
    - Elijah Muhammad, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 54)
    - Report on the CIA, 1975 (Box 526, Folder 55)
    - Black History, 1975-02 (Box 545, Folder 1)
    - US Foreign Policy, 1975 (Box 545, Folder 2)
    - What It Means to be an Afro-American Today, 1975-02-05 (Box 526, Folder 56)
    - Why I Am Anti-CIA, 1975-02-19 (Box 526, Folder 57)
    - News Broadcast, 1975-04-05 (Box 526, Folder 58)
    - Broadcasting-An Short Autobiography of Sly Stone, 1975-03-15 (Box 526, Folder 59)
    - To Give Advice to a Young Friend about to Enter High School, 1975-12-09 (Box 526, Folder 60)
    - Black Studies notebook, 1976-1977 (Box 531, Folder 15)
    - Asia, 1976 (Box 526, Folder 61)
    - Islam in Africa, 1976 (Box 526, Folder 62)
    - The Nation of Islam, 1976 (Box 531, Folder 27)
    - Power to the Streetgangs, 1976 (Box 526, Folder 21)
    - Information on Street Gangs, 1976 (Box 526, Folder 65)
    - Street Gangs Beware, 1976 (Box 526, Folder 66)
    - A Little Knowledge of How Life Is in the South and South East Bronx, 1976 (Box 526, Folder 67)
    - John F. Kennedy High School Graduation Program, 1976-06 (Box 526, Folder 63)
    - Math 1700 exam, 1976-11-10 (Box 526, Folder 64)
    - Law Book #1, 1977 (Box 522, Folder 6)
    - Criminology textbook, 1977 (Box 533, Folder 13)
  - Africa Trip, 1975
    - Africa trip essay, 1975 (Box 531, Folder 16)
    - My Trip to Alkebulan (Mother Africa and Europe), 1975 (Box 531, Folder 19)
    - My Trip to Brussels in Belgium, 1975 (Box 531, Folder 20)
    - Africa journal, 1975-08 (Box 531, Folder 17)
    - Members of the Europe and West Africa Observation Team, UNICEF, 1975-08 (Box 531, Folder 18)
  - Soul Scrapbooks and Music Writing, 1970-1978
    - Lyrics, 1970 (Box 524, Folder 14)
      Notebook of hand-transcribed lyrics by Sly and the Family Stone, the Isley Brothers, the Jackson 5, and others.
    - Study up on group singers, 1970 (Box 522, Folder 10)
    - Sly and the Family Stone concert, 1971 (Box 531, Folder 22)
    - Soul Book, 1971 (Box 523, Folder 4)
      Notebook- handwritten lyrics on ruled paper, 70 pp
    - Soul Book of Hit Songs Right On, 1971 (Box 523, Folder 3)
    - Song and Soul and Rock Book #1, 1972 (Box 522, Folder 9)
    - Soul Picture Book #2, 1972 (Box 522, Folder 2)
      Notebook- newspaper clippings of soul musicians taped onto pages.
    - Soul Song Book #4, 1972 (Box 522, Folder 3)
      Notebook- handwritten lyrics on ruled paper
    - Sly and the Family Stone scrapbook, 1973 (Box 531, Folder 23)
    - My Album Numbers, 1977 (Box 523, Folder 5)
      Notebook
    - Song list notebook, 1978 (Box 531, Folder 25)
    - List of artists, Undated (Box 531, Folder 21)
    - Songs/movies notebook, Undated (Box 531, Folder 24)
  - Notebooks and Miscellaneous Manuscripts, 1969-1985
    - Story book, 1969 (Box 523, Folder 2)
    - Phone book and addresses, 1970 (Box 524, Folder 11)
    - Clippings on gangs, 1972-1973 (Box 545, Folder 14)
      Photocopied news articles about gangs.
    - Black Education to Know About, Bambaataa-Khayan-Aasim, 1975 (Box 522, Folder 7)
    - Black History Self Education, 1975 (Box 522, Folder 5)
    - Poems and Storys, 1975 (Box 522, Folder 4)
      Includes versions of poems and stories, some of which are duplicated in the Homework and Lyrics subseries.
    - Hakim-a-Jamar Bar, Book of Self- Education, 1976 (Box 522, Folder 8)
    - Muslim Scrap Book #1, 1976 (Box 523, Folder 1)
    - My name is Bambaataa, 1976 (Box 524, Folder 13)
    - Teachings of the Honorable Elijah Muhammad Minister Louis Farrakhan, 1978 (Box 524, Folder 3)
    - UZN chapter members and rules, 1978-1979 (Box 531, Folder 26)
    - Book of Self Education #2- Religions, 1979 (Box 522, Folder 11)
    - Green notebook, 1980 (Box 523, Folder 6)
      Includes notes from criminal justice coursework, UZN agenda items, and lyrics.
    - Youth in S.A.V.E Under Ronnie, 1980 (Box 522, Folder 1)
      Contains identifying information. Access restricted to permission of the curator.
    - Zulu Funk Book, 1980 (Box 523, Folder 8)
      Notebook including lyrics, black history coursework, and record lists.
    - Application for Readmission, John Jay College, 1980-08-21 (Box 545, Folder 13)
    - The Pied Piper of Rap draft, 1982; Hager, Steven (Box 533, Folder 12)
    - Trapper, 1983-11 (Box 550)
    - The Universal Zulu Nation Infinity Lessons (drafts), 1985 (Box 523, Folder 7)
    - Miscellaneous manuscripts, Undated (Box 524, Folder 8)
      Includes album credits, contacts, Infinity Lessons, and other handwritten documents.
    - Reading list, Undated (Box 524, Folder 12)
    - Savage Spades notebook, Undated (Box 533, Folder 11)
    - Set lists, Undated (Box 531, Folder 5)
    - Yellow notebook, Undated (Box 524, Folder 5)
      Notebook containing lyrics and finances.
    - Zulu Members notebook, Undated (Box 533, Folder 10)
      Contains list of Zulu Imperial members and drafts of early infinity lessons
  - Lyrics and Poems, 1974-1984
    - Black Power, Undated (Box 524, Folder 9)
    - Copies for rehears/For funk family, Undated (Box 545, Folder 6)
    - D.E.P.H. Da Majesty notebook, Undated (Box 531, Folder 2)
    - Danger-Drugs, Undated (Box 531, Folder 1)
    - Funky Music Rocks On, Undated (Box 524, Folder 7)
    - Get Down, Move Around, 1974-03-21 (Box 531, Folder 3)
    - Look Out America, Undated (Box 531, Folder 4)
    - Lyrics portfolio, Undated (Box 547)
    - Notebook with lyrics, Undated (Box 523, Folder 9)
    - Red notebook, Undated (Box 524, Folder 4)
    - Soul, Undated (Box 524, Folder 10)
    - Stanga, Undated (Box 531, Folder 6)
    - Sweden Hotels notebook, Undated (Box 531, Folder 7)
    - Untitled, Undated (Box 531, Folder 8)
  - Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1973-1980
    - Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1973 (Box 533, Folder 1)
    - Bronx River Alternatives to Detention Program, 1974-1975 (Box 533, Folder 2)
    - Bronx River Alternatives to Detention Program, 1974-1975 (Box 533, Folder 3)
    - Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1975 (Box 533, Folder 4)
    - Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1976 (Box 533, Folder 5)
    - Bronx River Center permit and Hostos class schedule, 1978 (Box 533, Folder 6)
    - Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1979 (Box 533, Folder 7)
    - Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1980 (Box 533, Folder 8)
    - Bronx River petition, Undated (Box 533, Folder 9)
  - Phone and Contact Lists, 1975-1991
    - Bronx River/Zulu Nation names and addresses, 1975-1980 (Box 544, Folder 10)
    - Contacts, 1991 (Box 531, Folder 29)
    - Address book, Undated (Box 531, Folder 30)
    - Business cards, Undated (Box 546, Folder 21)
    - Contacts and addresses, Undated (Box 531, Folder 28)
    - Mailing lists, Undated (Box 544, Folder 9)
    - Notebook with addresses, Undated (Box 524, Folder 1)
    - Unbound notebook with addresses, Undated (Box 524, Folder 2)
    - Undated mail, Undated (Box 544, Folder 8)
- Flyers, 1977-1985
  Volumes 1-2 are scrapbook albums that contain the earliest flyers in the collection which were preserved in Bambaataa's original non-chronological order. These flyers are listed out in the order in which they appear in each volume. Flyers in folders A, B, and C were sleeved and numbered by Boo Hooray and are arranged chronologically. Boo Hooray flyer numbers are listed for each item and indicate the physical order in which they appear in the portfolios.
  - Bronx River Neighborhood Center Sickle Cell Benefit, Undated; Bambaataa, Afrika (Box 550, Folder 2)
    2 copies.
  - For the First Time in Jersey…D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Jazzy Jay, D.J. Red Alert at Christopher Columbus Hall, 1981-06-27; Esquire, Buddy (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Jazzy Jay, D.J. Red Alert, Cosmic Force M.C.s, Soulsonic Force M.C.s.
    Paterson, New Jersey
  - Dance Music at T-Connection, 1981-05-15; Nubian Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa and Soul Sonic Foce M.C.s.
    Bronx, New York
  - We're Very Serious…About Rockin U' at Negril, 1982-03-11 (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Original Jazzy Jay, Grand Mixer DST and Infinity 4 MCs, Markey Cee and Sput.
    New York, New York
  - Bionic Boogie Dance Contest at T-Connection, 1981-05-29; Esquire, Buddy; Production3 Plus1 (Box 550, Folder 2)
  - Back by Popular Demand The One's Who Funk Up Any Land at Cava Foundation Center, 1981-10-23; Nubian Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Jazzy Jay, Red Alert, Soul Sonic Force, Cosmic Force M.C.'s
    Norwalk, Connecticut
  - Your Taste in Sound Skate Down at Wheels Roller Rink, 1982-04-14; Nubian Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Original Jazzy Jay, Red Alert, Jazzy 5ive M.C.s.
    Yonkers, New York
  - Must Be the Music Skate Affair at Bronx Skating Rink, 1982-02-27; Nubian Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Jazzy Jay, Red Alert, Jazzy 5ive M.C.s.
  - A Three Day Holiday Jam at T Connection, 1981-12-28-1981-12-29; Richie-T Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    Cold Crush Bro's, D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Jazzy-Jay, Red-Alert, Jazzy 5 Emcees
  - 3 The Hard Way at the E-Tremont Y Boys Club, Undated; M.B.C. 79'; Nubian Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Islam, D.J. Jazzy Jay, D.J. Superman, The Herculords, D.J. Clark Kent, D.J. J.C., D.J. Charlie Chase.
  - A Youth Night Super Jam, Christmas Day at the New Blue Room, Undated; Esquire, Buddy; Nubian Productions; Stonecity Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Jazzy Jay, D.J. Red Alert, Soulsonic Force M.C.s, Mr. Biggs, Pow-Wow, G.L.O.B.E.
  - Wheels of Steel Nite at Danceteria, 1982-03-30; KLB Production (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Jazzy Jay, Silverstar, Lil Marky Cee, Lil Sput.
  - Show Stoppers Funk Jam Disco at Bronx River Center, 1980-03-28; Nubian Productions; Tiny Productions; Jazzy Dee Productions (Box 550, Folder 2)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, G.M. Flash, Breakout and Baron.
  - A Friday the 13 Disco at John F Kennedy High, 1981-03-13; Charlie Whiz (Box 550, Folder 2)
    Cold Crushers, Dee Jau, Mr Dee, Fabulous 5 MC's, Cosmic Force MC's, and Rockwell.
  - In Concert at the Savoy Manor, 1981-12-11; Esquire, Buddy; Williams, Martin; Brown, Vernon J. (Box 550, Folder 2)
    Treacherous-3, Cold Crush Brothers, and T-Ski Valley.
    Reprint signed and numbered 175/250 by Buddy Esquire.
  - 10 Years of Wonderful Music: A Disco Tribute to James Brown at Bronxriver Comm. Center, 1977-11-11; Organization, The (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, His Zulu Nation, Zambo, Mr. Biggs, Queen Kenya
  - A Disco Tribute to Sly Stone at Bronx River Community Center, 1977-11-11; Organization, The (Volume 1)
  - Birthday Party for D.J. Kool Herc at 1590 Jerome Ave, 1978-04-28; Sparkle Productions (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa and his Zulu Nation
  - Jungle Rock City Freak Dance at the Audubon Ballroom, 1978-06-30 (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambu, Mr. Biggs, Kool D.J. Dee, Tyrone the Mixologist, D.J. Starski, D.J. Sinbad, D.J. Afrika Islam, Ed Larock, D.J. Afrika Khayan, Squirppy, D.J. Afrika Queen Lisa, Shelly, Zulu Nation
    Washington Heights, New York
  - The Zulu Queens from Parkchester and Lamburg Projects present Jungle Rock City at Junior High School 167 and Junior High School 123, 1978-05-15-1978-05-06; Zulu Queens (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zulu Nation, D.J. Frogg, Toad Nation
  - The Zulu Nation present their 3rd Annual Disco Tribute to James Brown "20 Years of Wonderful Music" at Bronxriver Comm. Center, 1978-11-10; Zulu Nation (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambo, M.C. Mr. Biggs
  - The Zulu Nation present their 3rd Annual Disco Tribute to Sly Stone at BronxRiver Comm. Center, 1978-11-10; Zulu Nation (Volume 1)
  - The Fly Five Zulu Queens Presents The Night of the Living Dead Funk Jam at Taft High School and Junior High School 123, 1978-05-25-1978-05-27; Fly Five Zulu Queens (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambu, Mr. Biggs
  - Spank, Freak, Funk Attack PT.R at I.S. 131, 1978-11-03; Sudanese Productions; Universals Star Productions (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Afrika Zambu, D.J. Sinbad, M.C. Mr. Biggs, Cholly Rock, Zulu Nation
  - Funk Attack '78 at I.S. 131, 1978-09-22; Nubian Productions; Caine Productions (Volume 1)
    D.J. Africa Bambaataa, Zambu, M.C. Mr. Biggs, Disco King Mario, Nicky Dee, M.C. Doc LaRock, The L. Brothers, Mean Gene, Theodore, M.C. Starsky, Keven Kev.
  - Fund Raising Disco Tribute in Memory of Our Own D.J. Ed LaRock at Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1978-08-19 (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambu, Mr. Biggs, D.J. Afrika Islam, D.J. Afrika Lil Khayan
  - Rock Jitterbug City at Riverview Towers, 1978-09-01; Bee-Bop; Ray-Ray; Starsky (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, M.C. Mr. Biggs, Zambu, The Half Pint, The Zulu Nation
  - The Coming of the Age of Funk Sounds-Part 1 at Junior High School 167, 1978-09-15; Nubian Productions (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Afrika Zambu, M.C. Mr. Biggs, Disco King Mario, D.J. Nicky Dee, M.C. Doc LaRock
  - Spankafreak Disco at James Monroe High School, 1978-10-13; Nubian Productions (Volume 1)
    Disco King Mario, D.J. Kendu + John, D.J. Africa Bambaataa, Zambu, M.C. Mr. Biggs, Chuck City Crew, Zulu Nation
  - Spank N Freak Boogiee at I.S. 131, 1978-09-29; Nubian Productions (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambu, M.C. Mr. Biggs, D.J. Sinbad, Disco King Mario, Nicky Dee, Kenny Ken, lil John, M.C. Hutch, The Cowboy
  - The Organization Invite You to Dance to the Music at Riverview Towers Houses, 1978-05-14; Organization, The (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, His Zulu Nation
  - Freak Out and Don't You Stop…Uptown Meets Downtown at Evander Charles High School, 1978-01-27 (Volume 1)
    D.J. Breakout, The Baron, D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambo, Mr. Biggs
  - Uptown Freak-Freak Boogie at the Spot; Downtown Freak-Freak Boogie at Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1978-01-20-1978-01-21 (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Islam, Ed La Rock, The Mayberry Crew, D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Afrika Zambo
  - A Summer Disco at Club Rhapsody, 1977-06-25; We II (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa and The Motivator
  - Soulsonic Funk Jam at Schuyler Community Center, 1977-04-23 (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Zambo, The Zulu Kings
  - PA-R-R-TY at Bronx River Community Center, 1977-04-29 (Volume 1)
  - Dance to the Music at Whitney Young Center, 1977-06-11; Organization, The (Volume 1)
  - A $100 Dollar Freak Contest and A D.J. Throwdown at J.H.S. 123, 1978-01-13; Bambaataa, Afrika; Zulu Nation (Volume 1)
    Disco King Mario, Cool D.J. Nicky Dee, Chuck Chuck City Crew vs. D.J. Afrika Islam, Ed. La. Rock, Mayberry Crew
  - Soulsonic Funk Jam at Bronx River Neighborhood Center, 1977-04-15 (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa and his Zulu Nation, D.J. Afrika Zambo and his Zulu Kings
  - The Mighty Zulu Nation Pays a Disco Tribute to Sly & The Family Stone at Bronx River Center, 1978-11-10; Zulu Nation (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambu n Mr. Biggs, Islam n Isaac n Sinbad, Khayan n Squirpy
  - A Boggie Nite at Buckner Towers, 1977-10-22; Fox Productions Ltd. (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bammbataa
  - D.J. Grandfunk and D.J. Freddie Rock at Sedgwick Community Center, 1978-04-21; Bambaataa, Afrika (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, D.J. Grandfunk, D.J. Freddie Rock
  - A Funky Bootzilla Sureshot at Bronx River Center, 1978-04-08; Zulu Nation; C.C. Crew (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa, Zambu, Mr. Biggs, Disco King Mario, Nicky Dee, Starsky
  - One Dollar Disco at Boston Secor Community Center, 1978-04-07; Zulu Nation (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Islam, Ed-LaRock, Mayberry Crew
  - African Liberation Week, 1977-05-02-1977-05-06; Hostos Community College Black Students Union (Volume 1)
    D.J. Afrika Bambaataa
  - Second Annual Freak-A-Thon at Tracey Towers, 1978-04-29; Foxy Lady (Volume 1)
    D.J. Africa Bambaata, Zulu Nation, D.J. Prince of Funk, Al "G"
  - Soul Power '77 at Junior High School 123, 1977-10-14; Black Willie; Winston; Red; Lil Monk; Zulu Queens (Volume 1)